# MOHAMED RAMADAN

#### Mobile Developer

Mansoura, Egypt · +201281100168

**Email** · **LinkedIn** · **GitHub** 

I love building projects, and I'm in love with open source. Focused on being better every day, I worked in mobile development for 4 years, with flutter 3 years ago, and since then I made 6 Flutter contributions to more applications android, iOS, and 2 websites. I am good in state management Provider, Getx, and bloc currently Learning PHP and building my Owen Mobile Game in my freeTime.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **NOV 2022 - NOW AS (TICHNICAL SUPPORT)**

## **FLUTTER DEVELOPER, ABL (REMOTLY)**

- Build Start app Main App.
- Produce clean, efficient code based on specifications.
- ❖ Build UI/UX.
- Add features.
- Produce clean, efficient code based on specifications.
- Recommend and execute improvements.

#### JUN 2022 – OCT 2022

## JUNIOR FLUTTER DEVELOPER, BRACKET MEDIA LTD (REMOTLY)

- Responsible for upgrading the app make it app support Null Safety
- Improve UI/UX
- Add features.
- Fixing bugs

#### JAN 2022 - JUN 2022

## JUNIOR FLUTTER DEVELOPER, CYPARTA

- Delivered a multi-platform mobile app integrating analytics
- Investigated unused packages, files, and assets of application releases resulting in a 10% decrease in application size.
- Updated the user interface to fit iPad sized devices resulting in a full-screen experience for users
- Emphasized the importance of building reusable components and responsive designs, which reduced the development time of the onboarding process marginally and improved overall code quality.

## JUN 2020 - DEC 2021

## IT SUPPORT & MOBILE DEV, ARAK

build the front-end of the Arak mobile app and website

## **EDUCATION**

#### **AUG 2021**

## **BACHELOR'S DEGREE, MU**

- ❖ Bachelor's Degree in bioinformatics from Mansoura University
- with a grade of (B-)
- with a grade of (A+) in graduation project

#### **AUG 2016**

**POST-PRIMARY EDUCATION, HIGH SCHOOL** 

## **SKILLS**

## **TECHNICAL SKILS**

- Dart
- o Flutter
- Clean Architecture
- Clean Code
- State Management (Provider, Getx, Bloc,)
- Object-Oriented Programming (OOP)
- Web Development
- Adobe Creative
- Microsoft Office
- o Familiarity with Flutter Flavors
- Experience with push notifications.
- o Experience using GitHub (GitFlow) and a similar Source Control.
- Familiarity with modern software development practice (CI/CD)
- Experience using payment getaways API's for (urWay, flutterWave, PayU, Paypal, PayStack).
- o Knowledge of modern authorization mechanisms, such as JSON Web Token.
- Good knowledge of using local databases within flutter (SQLite, Hive).
- Working knowledge of the general mobile landscape, architectures, trends, and emerging technologies.
- Experience developing integrations with common APIs (e.g., Firebase, Twitter, Facebook, Instagram, Stripe, Google, Apple, etc.).
- o Experience with Unit and U testing Understanding of the Agile Software Development Life Cycle.

## **SOFTSKILS**

- Time management
- Independent worker
- Detail oriented
- Creativity

- Troubleshooting
- Teamwork
- Critical thinking
- Communication

CSSPython

Java

Android

HTML

o SOLID Design Principles

Problem Solving

Software Design

## PERSONAL PROJECTS

## **♣** FREEDOC APP

- o Doctor appointment app
- o Freelance app for doctors.
- o Using Provider as State Management
- o Using Firebase fire Store as backend API
- o Support Arabic and English and French
- o Push Notification and reminder notification

# > APPLink (Click to View it on Google Play)

# **QUIZ WEBSITE**

- Our quiz app contains a total of six-screen, the login screen where a user submits their cardinalates and signup than the main screen called the Chapter screen Then topics then Question screen. Each question has 4 options once the user click on the option if the answer is correct then it turns green otherwise red. At the end score screen where you can check your
- o score. you can use these
- o cardinalities to login
- o username: test@me.com
- o password: mohamed2022
- <u>Link Website</u> (Click to View its web Page)

#### ARAK WEBSITE

- Digital marketing website the company so user can view it's pervious and current Projects
- Using Provider"
- o it's responsive for all platforms PC, tablet and mobile
- Link Website (Click to View its web Page)

#### **♣** AERA

- E-Commerce app on google play with fantastic features makes the app easy to use and easy to order and track your order quickly you can try it yourself
- o Using Google Maps API to locate user
- o Using Provider as State Management
- Using Firebase fire Store as backend API
- o We can add more than one merchant
- Support Arabic and English Languages
- o Admin can add edit and delete update Products from admin Panel
- o Every merchant has its own admin Panel
- o App support points after completed purchases
- o Admin can add points or delete
- o Support Create and Login using Google and Facebook
- o Push Notification
- App Link (Click to View it on Google Play) App Link (Click to View it on APP Store)



- o Application that allows you to efficiently manage your budget. The handling of the application is easy thanks its simple and intuitive interface.
- o Add an income for the month and update the amount
- o Add a planned expense for the month and update the real expense
- o Copy an income or expense from the current month to the next month.
- o Graph give you visualization to your expenses and income
- App Link (Click to View it on APP Store Soon on Google Play)

## **LAT APP**

- o Flutter Chat App Using Firebase Cloud Store
- o Implementation of new UI/UX for Auth Screens Like (Login, SignUp, ForgetPassword)
- o integrations with Firebase API
- o Push Notification
- App Link (Click to View its Repo on GitHub)

# **♣** FOOD RECAPI

- Just the Recipe eliminates the clutter from any recipe website and displays only the ingredients and instructions. Convert messy recipe blogs into simple, beautiful recipe cards.
- o Using Local Caching
- Image Picker
- > App Link (Click to View its Repo on GitHub)

## **CONTROBUT IN PROJECTS**

## **JUMPERS**

- o Fix API Problem
- o Add Chat to the app.
- o Improve UI Components
- o Fix App Bugs
- > App Still in development phase Website Link

#### **♣** DALEEL

- o Fix some UI problems
- Add notification.
- o Link app with API
- o Add Features
- o Improve UI Components
- o Fix App Bugs
- > App Link Google Play App Link App Store

# **♣** SADAKAT

- o Fix API Problems
- Add Features
- o Improve UI Components
- o Fix App Bugs
- > App Link Google Play App Link App Store

# **COMMUNILLIFE**

- o Add 5 Payment Gateways
- o Add in-app purchases for both android and iOS
- o integrations revenue CAT API
- o Add Facebook. Google and Apple Auth
- o Uploading App on google Play and App Store
- o Fix app Issues and bugs
- > App Link (Click to View it on Google Play) AppLink (Click to View on APP Store)

# **★** VOLUNTEER APP (TEKERAM)

- o integrations Google Maps API
- o integrations firebase API
- o Add Features
- o Improve UI Components
- o Fix app Issues and bugs
- > App Link (Click to View its Repo on GitHub)

# **DONATION APP (GERAS)**

- o integrations firebase API
- Add Features
- o Improve UI Components
- o Fix app Issues and bugs
- > App Link (Click to View its Repo on GitHub)

## **LANGUAGES**

- Arabic (Native)
- English (Good)